<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>James Tharpe</title>
    <link>https://www.jamestharpe.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on James Tharpe</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; James Tharpe; All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 06:24:27 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.jamestharpe.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Useful Docker Shortcut Commands</title>
      <link>https://www.jamestharpe.com/useful-docker-shortcut-commands/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 06:24:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jamestharpe.com/useful-docker-shortcut-commands/</guid>
      <description>Docker Shell Command &amp;ldquo;Shortcuts&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;ve been working with Docker a lot lately and have found it useful to note down a few &amp;ldquo;shortcut&amp;rdquo; commands to maintain my local images and containers, until I have them memorized. Here they are.
Start/Stop All Docker Containers This example starts then stops all containers:
$ docker start $(docker ps -aq) a12b34c5d678 b23c46d6e789 c34d57e7f790 $ docker stop $(docker ps -q) a12b34c5d678 b23c46d6e789 c34d57e7f790  Remove All Docker Images This example removes all Docker images:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hire Me</title>
      <link>https://www.jamestharpe.com/hire-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2017 05:51:57 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jamestharpe.com/hire-me/</guid>
      <description>Nerd for Hire Wouldn’t it be great if you had an extra brain to handle complex projects that you don’t have time for? Well, you can’t! So go with the next best thing: me.
I can help with virtually any project related to software development, web development, cloud management, marketing automation, and agile project management. Through my company, Onlinico, I can take on projects of virtually any size.
Services for Businesses Here are some things I can do for your business:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up my Hugo Website</title>
      <link>https://www.jamestharpe.com/setting-up-hugo-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2017 06:24:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jamestharpe.com/setting-up-hugo-website/</guid>
      <description>Moving my Website to Hugo I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to move my website off of WordPress and on to a static site generator. After building sites for several clients using Jekyll, I thought it would be nice to try something new.
Since my website has been very neglected, most of the content is outdated so I&amp;rsquo;m not going to bother moving much of it over. If I were, I might try the wordpress-to-hugo-exporter exporter.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>