<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>James Tharpe</title>
    <link>https://www.jamestharpe.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on James Tharpe</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 20:25:15 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.jamestharpe.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>PCF Spring Boot Environment Basics</title>
      <link>https://www.jamestharpe.com/pcf-spring-boot-environment-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 20:25:15 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jamestharpe.com/pcf-spring-boot-environment-basics/</guid>
      <description>Spring Boot Configuration on Cloud Foundry I took the PCF Cloud Native Developer four day course to prepare for the Pivotal Certified Java Developer exam. This was my first in-depth exposure to PCF and Spring (Boot, MVC, Cloud), so there was a lot to learn with little experience. I learned a lot and enjoyed the course.
In my last article, I shared my notes on Spring Boot and PCF basics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pivotal Cloud Foundry (PCF) with Spring Boot Basics</title>
      <link>https://www.jamestharpe.com/pcf-spring-boot-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 17:06:34 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jamestharpe.com/pcf-spring-boot-basics/</guid>
      <description>PCF Cloud Native Developer I took the PCF Cloud Native Developer four day course to prepare for the Pivotal Certified Java Developer exam. This was my first in-depth exposure to PCF and Spring (Boot, MVC, Cloud), so there was a lot to learn with little experience. I learned a lot and enjoyed the course.
The course is very hands-on: The instructors introduce a concept at a high level, then you and a pairing partner must implement it in a real application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Useful Git Aliases</title>
      <link>https://www.jamestharpe.com/useful-git-aliases/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 08:03:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jamestharpe.com/useful-git-aliases/</guid>
      <description>Git Aliases for Productivity A recent addition to by Automatic Development Environment Setup script were several Git aliases that help to speed things up. Here is how and why I set them up.
Start the Day with git pom The first step in most developer workflows is to run git pull origin master to ensure your local work is current with the main line of development. Shave a few seconds off this routine step by shortening the command to git pom:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serverless Framework: Contact form with TypeScript on AWS</title>
      <link>https://www.jamestharpe.com/serverless-aws-backend/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2017 12:10:14 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jamestharpe.com/serverless-aws-backend/</guid>
      <description>Create a Backend for a Static Frontend We recently launched the Crawlity website which, like jamestharpe.com, uses Hugo to generate a static site. There&amp;rsquo;s no database or template engine running on the server - just static files. Unlike jamestharpe.com, crawlity.com needs a back-end to accept contact form submissions. So how does one create a dynamic back-end for a static, &amp;ldquo;serverless&amp;rdquo; front-end?
Short answer: With the Serverless Framework!
Serverless Framework, or simply &amp;ldquo;Serverless&amp;rdquo;, is a provider-agnostic framework for defining the functions and events that make up your application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serverless Framework with TypeScript and AWS: Getting Started</title>
      <link>https://www.jamestharpe.com/serverless-typescript-getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2017 18:08:22 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jamestharpe.com/serverless-typescript-getting-started/</guid>
      <description>Serverless and TypeScript Serverless Framework, or simply &amp;ldquo;Serverless&amp;rdquo;, is an excellent provider-agnostic framework for defining the functions and events that make up your service. Once defined your events and functions are defined, Serverless deploys your service to the target cloud provider by automatically provisioning the required infrastructure and deploying the application to it.
While getting started, I found that most Serverless Framework examples are in JavaScript. However, I prefer the strong-typing and smarter tooling of TypeScript so I made it my mission to write a simple Serverless microservice using Serverless and TypeScript.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker: Fix Invalid Bind Mount Spec in Git Bash</title>
      <link>https://www.jamestharpe.com/docker-fix-invalid-bind-mount-spec-gitbash/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2017 13:44:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jamestharpe.com/docker-fix-invalid-bind-mount-spec-gitbash/</guid>
      <description>Error response from daemon: invalid bind mount spec The call to docker run using Git Bash on Windows was recently frustrating me when I tried to specify a volume using -v:
$ docker run -it -v /c/Users/james/Code/my-application:/app james/testcontainer sh C:\Program Files\Docker\Docker\Resources\bin\docker.exe: Error response from daemon: invalid bind mount spec &amp;quot;/C/Users/james/Code/my-application;C:\\Program Files\\Git\\app&amp;quot;: invalid volume specification: &#39;/C/Users/james/Code/my-app;C:\Program Files\Git\app&#39;: invalid mount config for type &amp;quot;bind&amp;quot;: invalid mount path: &#39;\Program Files\Git\app&#39; mount path must be absolute.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Make Code Comments in Markdown</title>
      <link>https://www.jamestharpe.com/code-comments-markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 18:17:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jamestharpe.com/code-comments-markdown/</guid>
      <description>How to Comment a Markdown File Markdown doesn&amp;rsquo;t include specific syntax for comments, but there is a workaround using the reference style links syntax. Using this syntax, the comments will not be output to the resulting HTML.
Here are a few examples:
[]: # (This is a comment) []: # &amp;quot;And this is a comment&amp;quot; []: # &#39;Also this is a comment&#39; [//]: # (Yet another comment) [comment]: # (Still another comment)  Each of these lines works the same way:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Include Files Outside Docker Build Context</title>
      <link>https://www.jamestharpe.com/include-files-outside-docker-build-context/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 17:33:25 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jamestharpe.com/include-files-outside-docker-build-context/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Forbidden path outside the build context&amp;rdquo; I was recently attempting to Dockerize a Node project, so I added a docker folder to the project and created a simple Dockerfile to get started:
FROM node:alpine WORKDIR /app COPY ../ ./ RUN npm install EXPOSE 80 ENTRYPOINT [ &amp;quot;npm&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;start&amp;quot; ]  However, when I tried to build the image, I got the following output:
$ docker build -t nodeapp . Sending build context to Docker daemon 53.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatic Development Environment Setup</title>
      <link>https://www.jamestharpe.com/automatic-development-environment-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2017 11:42:46 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jamestharpe.com/automatic-development-environment-setup/</guid>
      <description>How to Automate Your Development Environment Setup Starting from a fresh OS installation, manually installing and configuring a full development environment can take several days. Even then, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to forget some bit of configuration or to install some critical software. By following the GROWS everything in version control practice, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to save a ton of time and minimize disruption by automating the process.
Most of the software I write is developed on Windows, so I decided to write the script using PowerShell and Chocolatey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Useful Docker Shortcut Commands</title>
      <link>https://www.jamestharpe.com/useful-docker-shortcut-commands/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 06:24:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jamestharpe.com/useful-docker-shortcut-commands/</guid>
      <description>Docker Shell Command &amp;ldquo;Shortcuts&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;ve been working with Docker a lot lately and have found it useful to note down a few &amp;ldquo;shortcut&amp;rdquo; commands to maintain my local images and containers, until I have them memorized. Here they are.
Start/Stop All Docker Containers This example starts then stops all containers:
$ docker start $(docker ps -aq) a12b34c5d678 b23c46d6e789 c34d57e7f790 $ docker stop $(docker ps -q) a12b34c5d678 b23c46d6e789 c34d57e7f790  Remove All Docker Images This example removes all Docker images:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hire Me</title>
      <link>https://www.jamestharpe.com/hire-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2017 05:51:57 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jamestharpe.com/hire-me/</guid>
      <description>Nerd for Hire Wouldn’t it be great if you had an extra brain to handle complex projects that you don’t have time for? Well, you can’t! So go with the next best thing: me.
I can help with virtually any project related to software development, web development, cloud management, marketing automation, and agile project management. Through my company, Onlinico, I can take on projects of virtually any size.
Services for Businesses Here are some things I can do for your business:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up my Hugo Website</title>
      <link>https://www.jamestharpe.com/setting-up-hugo-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2017 06:24:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jamestharpe.com/setting-up-hugo-website/</guid>
      <description>Moving my Website to Hugo I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to move my website off of WordPress and on to a static site generator. After building sites for several clients using Jekyll, I thought it would be nice to try something new.
Since my website has been very neglected, most of the content is outdated so I&amp;rsquo;m not going to bother moving much of it over. If I were, I might try the wordpress-to-hugo-exporter exporter.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>